Email: applandsys@gmail.com | Cell: +8801837664478 | Skype: tariq4478

### **Profile:**

I work predominantly in full-stack development. My career started in 2012 and since then I have gained extensive experience in web design and development in a professional environment. I frequently work on Front-End and Back-End Development with complex interactions and integration with different Javascript Frameworks. I have key skills in usability, accessibility, State Management, API development, advanced PHP and Javascript-based front end and back end development, responsive design, mobile application, and user interface design using a range of web technologies. I work equally well alone and as part of a global multi-functional team. I have good practical, communication, and organizational skills, being a mentor and team leader. I'm currently employed by the **British American Resource Center.** as a Full-Stack Developer developing and maintaining their global marketing sites promoting the brand and products.

### Skills:

- ☐ Laravel, Livewire Codeigniter framework
- Cordova, React Native, Android Java
- React, Vue.js, Vuex, Redux
- WordPress Theme Development
- ☐ JSON, JSX, Web Components, XML
- ☐ Strong knowledge of JavaScript (ES6), HTML and CSS Flexbox, and Grid Layout.
- ☐ Front-end code optimization for best performance.
- ☐ API: Payment Api, Map, Hotel API, Facebook, Google etc
- Photoshop and Illustrator for Web needs.
- Search engine optimization.

## Other relevant experiences:

- □ Proficiency in PHP/ MYSQL/ MongoDB/ Sqlite/ Postgresql and AJAX .
- ☐ Hybrid apps development with Cordova
- □ Digital Ocean, AWS, etc Server.
- eCommerce and payment gateway integration.
- ☐ Git, Bitbucket
- Data Scraping
- ☐ Accounting knowledge
- ☐ ISP and Mikrotik API
- LMS development knowledge
- Landing page design principles
- ☐ Fluent in English Conversation.

# Work Experience:

Front end Web and Backend Developer, British American Resource Center, 2019 - Till date

Front end Web Developer, *Falcon Infotech,* 2017 - 2019

Front end Web & Mobile Apps Developer, Softexpertz, 2014 - 2017

Front end Web Developer, NI Biz Soft Solution, 2012 - 2014

## **Education:**

MBA National University, Dhaka, Bangladesh 2nd class

BBA National University, Dhaka, Bangladesh 2nd class

HSC (Business) Technical and Commercial College 1st Division

SSC (Science) Jessore Board 2nd Division